Guide to the Amos Alonzo Stagg Papers 1866-1964
University of Chicago Library
- Series IX: Books, Journals and Ephemera
  - Subseries 1: Books and Journals
    - Brothers, Richard. A Revealed Knowledge of the Prophecies and Times, Book the First Wrote Under the Direction of the Lord God and Published (First Sign of Warning for the Benefit of all Nations Containing Great and Remarkable Things Not Revealed to Any Other Person on Earth) the Restoration of the Hebrews to Jerusalem, 1798.
    - Rules of Golf.
    - Blake, I.H. Scientific Boxing, Official Textbook by the Amateur Athletics Union of Canada, 1922.
    - The Scottish Tartans with Historical Sketches of the Clans and Families of Scotland
    - Schaible, Charles H., M.D. The Systematic Training of the Body, 1878
    - Tales of Humor.
    - Stagg, Amos Alonzo and Wesley W. Stout. Touchdown! Two 1927 editions.
    - Reynolds, James, Samuel Fisher and Henry B. Wright, editors. Two Centuries of Christian Activity at Yale, 1907.
    - Heydrick, Benjamin, editor. Types of the Short Story: Selected Stories with Readings and Lists, 1913.
    - University of Chicago Songbook, 1920.
    - University of Chicago Songbook, 1927.
    - Shepard, Thomas G. Yale Glees. A Collection of the Songs Used by Yale Glee Club, 1893.
  - Subseries 2: Ephemera
    - High School Memorabilia 1866-1882 (Folder 1-14 and Oversize Folders 1-2) - This scrapbook begins with a letter declaring the oath of office and a ballot for Amos L. Stagg’s (father to A.A Stagg) appointment to the office of Constable for Orange, N.J, 1866. The remaining scrapbook contains Orange, N.J baseball league scores, notices, and a written history of Orange in addition to a collection of Stagg’s compositions, history, arithmetic, spelling, geography and grammar assignments and examinations. Also included is a Santa Claus picture book (1879) and Stagg’s sketch book, penmanship books, workbooks and copybooks from his tenure at Orange High School circa 1879-1882. (see Box 338 for oversized items) (Box 326)
    - High School Memorabilia 1875 St. Mark’s Public School - This scrapbook contains assignments, spelling lessons, compositions and maps of New Jersey written and drawn by Amos Alonzo Stagg at the St. Mark’s Public School. It also contains his report cards and cross-stitch pieces. (Box 327)
    - Telegrams 1932-1946 (1 Additional Folder) - This is a scrapbook consisting only of telegrams to Stagg and includes an offer to join the College of the Pacific, his acceptance and numerous congratulations and best wishes. (Box 327)
    - Yale Glee Club 1883-1889 (Folders 1-9) - This scrapbook contains music and programs for the Yale Glee Club performances. It also houses advertisements, resolutions, banquet menus and a series of newspaper clippings that review the Glee Club. (Box 328)
    - Yale and University of Chicago Memorabilia 1888-1901 (Folders 1-3) - This box contains a set of 1901 tinted and color-washed photos of Stagg, the track team, Hitchcock Hall, Bartlett Gym, Marshall Field and copies of the Illustrated Horoscope, Mitchell’s Ancient Atlas, and Yale Record 1890. It also contains programs for 1888 Yale Football Team Dinner and “A Great Hall Celebration” for City College of New York and a set of penmanship samples. (Box 329)
    - University of Chicago Ticket Scrapbook 1896-1914 - This volume consists of season ticket stubs and booklets for football, baseball, track, gymnastic tournaments and interscholastic meets. Also included are press passes and tickets, athletic schedules, baseball club and association passes, programs and flyers for sporting events at the University of Chicago and an invitation to the opening exercises and ceremonies for Bartlett Gymnasium. (Box 330)
    - Football and Coaching 1890-1905, 1927 and 1932 (1 Additional Folder and Oversize Folders 1-2) (see Box 338 for oversized items) - Includes Football Rules Committee, articles on developing teams and coaching, how to play football, articles on Stagg at YMCA Training School and Yale Football. Also includes histories and the development of football, University of Chicago football 1893-1905, William Rainey Harper and athletics, reform in college sports, advertisements for Yale baseball and copies of the Chicago Tribune Oct. 21-22, 1890. (Box 331)
    - University of Chicago Baseball Trip to Japan, 1915 (Folders 1-3 and 1 Oversize Folder) - This collection consists of a scrapbook, loose photographs and various menus and programs from the 1915 University of Chicago Baseball team tour of the Orient and games with Waseda University in Japan. It also covers games in the Philippines, Hawaii and China and includes Japanese newspaper accounts and a copy of The Maroon. The photographs document the team’s trip on an ocean liner, their games, Japanese men and women circa 1915 and games. They also include pictures on the team en route to the West Coast via Montana, Oregon and Spokane, Washington. (see Box 338 for oversized items) (Box 331)
    - University of Chicago Ticket Scrapbook 1896-1914 (Folders 1-14) - These are the remaining pages of the ticket scrapbook and contain more stubs, booklets and schedules for football, baseball and track events at the University of Chicago. (Box 332)
    - University of Chicago Athletic Schedules 1899-1922 - This is a scrapbook that contains only small souvenir athletic schedules for baseball, football, track, basketball and swimming games and meets at the University of Chicago. It also includes an official Big Ten Football schedule. (Box 333)
    - College of the Pacific vs. Notre Dame Oct. 5, 1940 (Oversize Folders 1-3) - This scrapbook includes coverage of the Pacific vs. Notre Dame game, features on the late Knute Rockne. (see Box 338 for oversized items) (Box 333)
    - University of Chicago Football Memorabilia - grid iron press-plate with a 55 yard line, circa 1900? (Box 334)
    - Photographs, Posters and Cartoons 1916-1924 - Includes oversize photographs of Stagg Field during football games, the 1921 and 1924 football squad and the University of Chicago campus. Also contains oversize cartoons on Stagg and the football team and posters advertising Stagg lectures. (Box 335)
    - Olympic Games Scrapbook 1924 (Folders 1-2 and 1 Oversize Folder) - Contains newspaper clippings covering events, personalities and winner standings of the 1924 Olympic Games in Paris. It includes women’s games, programs, menus, notes, summaries, Olympic Committee programs, bills, telegrams (including one from President Calvin Coolidge), U.S. Lines luggage tags and passenger lists and Olympics programs. (see Box 338 for oversized items) (Box 336)
    - Order of “C” 400 Bound Letters 1933 - This is a bound in leather book of four hundred letters written to Stagg between May and June of 1933 from former University of Chicago athletes and “C” Men. Letters illustrate friendship and well wishes to Stagg on the occasion of his retirement from the University of Chicago. (Box 337)
    - Oversize items (Box 338)